Finding Aid for College of Engineering (University of Michigan) publications, 1873-2015
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sub-Unit Publications
  Included under the heading "Department" is material from defunct engineering departments such as Descriptive Geometry and Drawing, Geodesy and Surveying, and Geology. (Current departments with separate publication groups in the archives are listed on the following page.) The Program in Technical Communication is filed under the former name of Department of Humanities. Under Development Office the researcher will find brochures and reports describing various building needs and programs. There are also publications from the various development campaigns including the Capital Campaign in the 1970s and the M Campaign in the 1990s. The Honor Code brochures describe in detail the points of the Honor Code and the requirements placed on students and faculty in observance of the Honor Code. These brochures are published by the Honor Council. The Industry Program publications include abstracts, directories, proceedings, and reports.
  There is also extensive material from the Minority Engineering Programming Office (MEPO) and its predecessor the Minority Projects Office. These include annual reports, newsletters, and reports documenting MEPO's function in reaching out to minority high school students and mentoring minority engineering students. Reports from the North Campus Planning Committee describe the need for space and include preliminary floor plans for buildings to be built to house College of Engineering departments and labs. Publications from the 1970s from the Office of the Dean, such as the Newsletter, Ingenor, Technium, and Technium+, are found in this series. Printed material from the Tauber Manufacturing Institute (TMI), a collaborative effort with the School of Business Administration and industry will be found in a separate publications group under the title Joel D. Tauber Manufacturing Institute (University of Michigan).
  - Accreditation Board of Engineering and Technology
    - Reports
      - Questionnaire for Review of Engineering Programs, Volume 1, 1981 (Box 9)
      - Aerospace Engineering and Chemical Engineering 1981, 2 volumes (Box 9)
      - Civil Engineering and Computer Engineering 1981, 2 volumes (Box 9)
      - Electrical Engineering 1981 (Box 9)
      - Engineering Physics and Environmental Sciences 1982, 2 volumes (Box 9)
      - Industrial and Operations Engineering and Materials and Metallurgical Engineering 1981, 2 volumes (Box 9)
      - Mechanical Engineering and Applied Mechanics 1981 (Box 9)
      - Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering and Nuclear Engineering 1981, 2 volumes (Box 9)
      - Self-Study Questionnaire for Review of Engineering Programs
        - 1987 (Box 9)
        - 1993 (Box 9)
  - Alumni Relations
    - Newsletters
      - Alumni News
        - The Environmental Problem (pre-print), 1970 (Box 9)
    - Reports
      - Memoranda on the Opportunities and Development of the College of Engineering, 1916 (Box 9)
    - Individual Alumni Clubs
      - Chicago Alumni Directory Committee
        - Directories
          - University of Michigan College of Engineering Chicago Area Alumni Directory, 1975 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1904
        - Directories
          - Directory of the Engineering Class of 1904, 1930-1965, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Class of 1917
        - Constitution undated (Box 9)
        - Directories
          - 60th Anniversary Directory, 1977 (Box 9)
        - Newsletters
          - The 17E Alumni News, 1977 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1918
        - Directories
          - 1958 Roster, 1958 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1921
        - Directories
          - Class of '21, 1961 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1924
        - Directories
          - 1924'E Class Record, 1964 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1925
        - Directories
          - '25 Engineers, [1976] (Box 9)
      - Class of 1931
        - Brochures
          - Engineering Class Scholarship Program Academic Awards for Undergraduates, 1993 (Box 9)
        - Directories
          - M 31E, [1977] (Box 9)
      - Class of 1932
        - Photograph with Identification 1977 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1933
        - Directories
          - Directory of 1933 Engineering, 1983 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1934
        - Directories
          - Class of 1935e College of Engineering Class Directory (Box 9)
      - Class of 1938
        - Certificates 1987 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1942
        - Directories
          - Fiftieth Anniversary Reunion, 1992 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1947
        - Directories
          - Engineering Class of 1947 Class Handbook, 1997 (Box 9)
          - 55th Anniversary Handbook, 2002 (Box 9)
          - 60th Anniversary Handbook, 2007 (Box 9)
        - Newsletters
          - 1947 Engineers Silver Anniversary Reunion, 1972 (Box 9)
      - Class of 1948
        - Directories
          - Class of 1948E Emeritus Reunion, 1998 (Box 10)
      - Class of 1949
        - Directories
          - Class of 1949 Emeritus Reunion, 1999 (Box 10)
      - Class of 1957
        - Directories
          - Class of 1957E 40th Class Reunion, 1997 (Box 10)
      - Class of 1958
        - Directories
          - Class of 1958E 40th Class Reunion, 1998 (Box 10)
      - Class of 1972
        - Directories
          - Class of 1972E 25th Class Reunion, 1997 (Box 10)
      - Class of 1973
        - Directories
          - Class of 1973E 25th Class Reunion, 1998 (Box 10)
      - Class of 1987
        - Directories
          - Class of 1987E 10th Class Reunion, 1997 (Box 10)
      - Class of 1988
        - Directories
          - Class of 1988E 10th Class Reunion, 1998 (Box 10)
      - Class of 1992
        - Directories
          - Class of 1992E 5th Class Reunion, 1997 (Box 10)
      - Class or 1993
        - Directories
          - Class of 1993E 5th Class Reunion, 1998 (Box 10)
      - Engineering Alumni of Chicago
        - Reports
          - Memorandum on the Opportunities for the Development of the Colleges of Engineering and Architecture and General Recommendations Thereon by the Entire Technical Graduate Body of the University of Michigan, 1916 (Box 10)
      - New York Area Directory Committee
        - Directories
          - New York Area Alumni Directory, 1975 (Box 10)
      - Southern California Directory Committee
        - Directories
          - Southern California Area Alumni Directory, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Alumni Society
    - Programs 1994-2000 (Box 10)
  - Ann Arbor Industry-Education Symposium
    - Programs 1960-1964 (Box 10)
  - Applied Mathematics, Program in
    - Brochures 1957-1976 (Box 10)
  - Associate Dean for Instruction
    - Bulletins
      - Bulletin, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Automotive Research Center
    - Annual Reports
      - Scientific and Technical Report Summary, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Bioengineering Program
    - Brochures 1976-1979, undated (Box 10)
    - Newsletters
      - Bioengineering Student Newsletter, 1974, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Biomedical Engineering Department
    - Manuals
      - Graduate Student Handbook 1996-1997, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Center for Display Technology and Manufacturing
    - Proceedings
      - Flat Panel Display Strategic Forum "Creating a U.S. Industry", 1994 (Box 10)
  - Center for Ergonomics
    - Brochures undated (Box 10)
  - Center for Machine Intelligence
    - Flyers undated (Box 10)
  - Center for Parallel Computing
    - Brochures undated (Box 10)
  - Center for Professional Development
    - Newsletters
      - Re: Engineering, News From the Center for Professional Development, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Center for Research on Integrated Manufacturing (CRIM)
    - Brochures 1982-1986 (Box 10)
    - Directories
      - Faculty Profiles--Fields of Expertise, undated (Box 10)
    - Reports
      - The Design of an End of Arm Tool Management System for Flexible Assembly Systems (FAS) Utilizing Industrial Robots by Paul G. Ranky, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Center for Robotics and Integrated Management (CRIM)
    - Annual Reports 1982-1983 (Box 10)
    - Brochures 1982-1984 (Box 10)
    - Bulletins
      - Robotics Research and Education at the University of Michigan, undated (Box 10)
    - Directories
      - Faculty Profiles--Fields of Expertise, undated (Box 10)
    - Integrated Design and Manufacturing Division
      - Bulletin 1984 (Box 10)
      - Directories
        - Directory of Research Projects and Investigators 1982 (Box 10)
    - Management Divisions Systems
      - Annual Reports 1982 (Box 10)
      - Reports
        - Research Directions in Robotics, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Commission on Undergraduate Engineering Education
    - Brochures
      - Michigan Undergraduate Engineering to the 21st Century: An Agenda for Innovative Engineering, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Committee of the Faculty
    - Reports
      - A Review of "A Study of Engineering Graduates and Former Students, Non-Graduates, Made by a Committee of the Faculty of the Colleges of Engineering and Architecture, at the University of Michigan", undated. (Box 11)
  - Computer Aided Engineering Network (CAEN)
    - Brochures
      - 1980-1997 undated (Box 11)
      - Camp CAEN, 1995-1996 (Box 11)
    - Flyers 1993 (Box 11)
    - Histories 1983 (Box 11)
    - Manuals
      - CAEN Handbook: A User's Guide to CAEN Services, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
      - CAEN Handbook, 1991-1998, 6 folders (Box 11)
      - Student Handbook, 1985, 6 folders (Box 11)
      - Users Guide, 1987 (Box 11)
    - Newsletters
      - Apollo Newsletter, vol. 1-2, 1985 (Box 11)
      - CAEN Faculty Newsletter, vol. 1-2, 1984-1986 (Box 11)
      - CAEN Newsletter, vol. 2-18, 1985-2001, 17 folders (Box 11)
      - CAEN Student Newsletter, 1984-1986 (Box 11)
      - CAEN Technical Note, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Prospectus
      - A Plan for the Computer Aided Engineering Network and North Campus Instructional Complex, 1983, 2 volumes (Box 11)
    - Reports
      - The Computer Aided Engineering Network: An Experiment in Computer Enhanced Productivity, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Industrial Affiliates Program
      - Brochures undated (Box 11)
  - Continuing Engineering Education
    - Brochures
      - 1968-1992 (Box 11)
      - Update '80 Bendix Corporation and College of Engineering, 1980 (Box 11)
      - Update '84 Allied Corporation and the University of Michigan College of Engineering, 1984 (Box 11)
      - Update '87 Allied-Signal and the University of Michigan College of Engineering, 1987 (Box 11)
    - Bulletins 1991 (Box 11)
  - Cooperative Education Program
    - Brochures 1990, undated (Box 11)
  - Department of Descriptive Geometry and Drawing
    - Bulletins
      - Specifications--Descriptive Geometry Drawing, 1916-1919 (Box 11)
      - Specifications for Descriptive Geometry Drawing, undated (Box 11)
  - Department of Geodesy and Surveying
    - Manuals
      - Exercises in Plane Surveying (Revised Edition), 1923 (Box 12)
      - Exercises in Surveying, 1932 (Box 12)
  - Department of Geology
    - Syllabi
      - Syllabus of Lectures in Historical Geology for Engineers 1914-1920, 2 volumes (Box 12)
  - Department of Humanities
    - Brochures 1979 (Box 12)
    - Bulletins
      - Humanities and Social Science for Engineers, undated (Box 12)
    - Bulletins (Catalogs)
      - Suggested Undergraduate Courses, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Lecture Series
      - Programs 1978 (Box 12)
    - Lectures on Current Issues
      - Programs 1974-1981 (Box 12)
    - Newsletters
      - Newsnotes, 1972-1974 (Box 12)
      - The Tennessee Williams Newsletter, 1979, 1981 (Box 12)
    - Writing Awards
      - Brochures 1975-1977 (Box 12)
      - Regulations 1976-1978 (Box 12)
  - Department of Mechanism and Engineering Drawing
    - Reports
      - Benefits Derived From the Segregation of Students in Technical Subjects on the Basis of Ability, Characteristics of Good and Poor Students: A Report on Investigations Conducted by the Department of Mechanism and Engineering Drawing, University of Michigan, 1923 to 1925, undated (Box 12)
  - Development
    - Development
      - Brochures undated (Box 12)
      - Citations
        - Dedication of the Automotive Engineering Laboratory and the Aeronautical Engineering Laboratory, 1957 (Box 12)
      - Memorandum
        - A Commitment to Restore an Equitable Level of General Fund Support for the College of Engineering, 1984 (Box 12)
      - Prospectus
        - Building I (Including Summary of Revised Plan for North Campus Engineering Complex), 1981 (Box 12)
      - Reports
        - Comprehensive Development Plan, 1983-1985, 1983 (Box 12)
        - Endowment Objectives, undated (Box 12)
        - Engineering and Technology Center, Building I North Campus, Program Statement, 1969 (Box 12)
        - Plans for Developing an Engineering and Technology Center on North Campus, 1966 (Box 12)
        - Program Statement North Campus Engineering and Technology Center Building I, 1969 (Box 12)
        - Project Analysis Engineering Building I-A, 1971 (Box 12)
        - Site and Building Plans for an Engineering and Technology Center, 1967 (Box 12)
        - University Fund-Raising and Its Relation to the College of Engineering at the University of Michigan, 1946 (Box 12)
    - Surveys
      - College of Engineering of the University of Michigan: A Survey of Fund Raising Sources and a Plan of Campaign, 1948 (Box 12)
    - Buildings
      - Ann and Robert H. Lurie Tower Carillon 1996, undated, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Chrysler Center 1967, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
      - Engineering Center Building
        - Drawings 1992 (Box 12)
      - Francois-Xavier Bagnoud Building 1993 (Box 12)
      - Herbert H. Dow 1980-1983, undated (Box 12)
      - Irwin Chase Plaza Dedication, 2001 (Box 12)
      - Mortimer E. Cooley Memorial undated (Box 12)
    - Development Campaigns
      - Campaign for Michigan
        - Brochures 1984 (Box 12)
      - Capital Campaign
        - Briefing Papers 1978 (Box 12)
        - Brochures
          - 1974-1976 (Box 12)
          - A Program to Strengthen Engineering Education at the University of Michigan, undated (Box 12)
          - A Tradition of Engineering Leadership, undated (Box 12)
        - Manuals
          - Worker's Guide, 1975 (Box 12)
        - Newsletters
          - News, 1974-1977 (Box 12)
        - Press Releases and News Clippings 1974-1978 (Box 12)
        - Reports
          - Report of Study and Recommendations for a Capital Gifts Campaign, 1972 (Box 12)
          - Interim Report and Campaign Plan, [ca. 1975] (Box 12)
          - Capital Campaign Final Report, 1979 (Box 12)
      - M Campaign
        - Brochures undated (Box 12)
        - Newsletters
          - Impact, 1992-1994 (Box 12)
        - Programs
          - Design for Impact Campaign Donor Recognition Dinner, 1994 (Box 12)
        - Reports
          - Campaign Executive Committee 1992 (Box 12)
    - Endowed Professorships Program
      - Programs
        - Endowed Professorship Dinner, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Engineering Alumni Society
      - Programs
        - Alumni Society Awards Dinner, 1992-1993 (Box 13)
  - Electron Microbeam Analysis Laboratory
    - Brochures 1988 (Box 13)
  - Engineering Career Resource Center
    - Annual Reports 1999-2000 (Box 13)
    - Brochures undated (Box 13)
    - Manuals
      - Career Manual, 2001-2002 (Box 13)
  - Engineering Communications
    - Surveys
      - 1995 Communication Survey: Findings, Recommendations, Next Steps, 1996 (Box 13)
  - Engineering Industrial Support Program
    - Brochures undated (Box 13)
    - Newsletters
      - EISP at a Glance, 1982-1985, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Reports
      - An Evaluation of the Engineering Industrial Support Program for 1978-79 by Mark D. Shermis and Elizabeth K. Gilliam, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Engineering Laboratories
    - Reports
      - University of Michigan Engineering Laboratories: A Status Report of the Industrial Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 13)
  - Engineering Libraries
    - Directories
      - Directory of Services and Policies, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Manuals
      - Library Guide, undated (Box 13)
  - Engineering Mechanics, Program in
    - Brochures 1959-1969 (Box 13)
  - Engineering Physics, Program in
    - Brochures 1953-1993, undated (Box 13)
  - Engineering Placement Service
    - Annual Reports
      - Annual Report of Engineering Placement, 1963-1978, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Annual Report of Engineering Placement and Cooperative Education, 1982-1987 (Box 13)
    - Brochures 1970-1979, undated (Box 13)
    - Manuals
      - Placement Manual, 1972-1987, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Engineering Science, Program in
    - Brochures undated (Box 13)
  - Engineering Summer Conferences
    - Brochures 1960-1969, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Bulletins 1972-1989, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Calendars
      - Chairman's Calendar for Courses Planned for 1989, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Manuals
      - Visitors Guide, undated (Box 13)
    - Texts
      - Design of Engineering Experiments, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Environmental Sciences Engineering, Program in
    - Brochures 1971-1978 (Box 13)
  - Engineering Transportation Library
    - Reports
      - Planning Constraints & Alternatives, 1981 (Box 13)
  - First Year Advising Office
    - Newsletters
      - Advising Matters, 1995-1997, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Freshman Counseling Office
    - Statistics
      - Freshman Statistics and Program Selection 1985-86 Through 1986-87 (Box 13)
  - GEM (National Consortium in Engineering and Science for Graduate Degrees for Minorities)
    - Annual Reports 1998 (Box 13)
    - Brochures undated (Box 13)
  - Great Lakes Trade Adjustment Assistance Center
    - Brochures undated (Box 13)
  - Honor Council
    - Brochures 1936-1992, undated (Box 13)
    - Programs 1962-1967 (Box 13)
    - Supplement
      - The Engineer's Oath: On Our Honor, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Industry Program
    - Abstracts
      - Industry Program Abstracts, 1970 (Box 14)
    - Brochures 1962, undated (Box 14)
    - Calendars
      - Calendar of Technical Meetings, 1962 (Box 14)
    - Directories
      - Photographic Roster of the Engineering Faculty, 1960-1969, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Proceedings
      - A New Approach to the Total Transportation Problem, 1965 (Box 14)
      - Sources of Radiation for Industry: Transcript of the First Ann Arbor Industry-Education Symposium, [1956] (Box 14)
    - Reports
      - Computer Components Development by D.C. Ray and H.L. Garner, 1957 (Box 14)
      - A Review of Nuisance and Hazardous Noise by S.S. Kushner, 1958 (Box 14)
      - The Use of Computers to Determine Time-Dependent Fission Product Distribution by John V. Nehemias, et al., 1955 (Box 14)
      - Wear Rates of Final Drive Sun Gear by Radioactive Method by Frank L. Schwartz, Robert H. Eaton, and Ardath H. Emmons, 1955 (Box 14)
  - Integrated Technology Instructional Center
    - Flyers 1994 (Box 14)
  - Interdisciplinary Engineering
    - Brochures 1990-1993 (Box 14)
  - Internationals Programs Office
    - Newsletters
      - Global Engineer, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Laboratory for Scientific Computation
    - Bulletins
      - Ph.D. Degree Program in Scientific Computation, [1989] (Box 14)
    - Flyers 1989 (Box 14)
    - Proceedings
      - Conference Proceedings of the Second Scientific Computation Poster Conference, 1992 (Box 14)
  - M-GM Key University Program
    - Annual Reports
      - Year-End Report, 1985-1990, 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Directories
      - Team Roster, undated, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Manufacturing Strategy Planning Group
    - Reports
      - COE-Industry Technology Exchange: Elements, Issues, and Strategy, 1992 (Box 14)
  - Manufacturing Systems Engineering
    - Brochures undated (Box 14)
  - Martin Luther King Day Committee
    - Programs 1990-2002 (Box 14)
  - Martin Luther King Day Workshop
    - Proceedings
      - 2001 A Career Odyssey...Who Will be the Leaders of the 21st Century, 1992 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Engineering Research Institute
    - Proposals
      - The Michigan Engineering Research Institute: A Prospectus to the Michigan Strategic Fund, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Engineering Television Network
    - Brochures undated (Box 14)
    - Bulletins
      - Course Guide and Information Booklet, 1988-1989 (Box 14)
      - Televised Courses, 1987 (Box 14)
  - Michigan-Life Conference on New Technologies in Transportation
    - Proceedings 1939 (Box 14)
  - Michigan State Police 800 MHz Radio System Study Committee
    - Report
      - Summary Report of the University of Michigan MSP 800 MHz Radio System Study Committee, 1992 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Technology Television Network
    - Proposals
      - The Michigan Technology Television Network: A Prospectus to the Michigan Strategic Fund, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Minority Engineering Program Office (MEPO)
    - Annual Reports
      - Three Year Report, 1984-1987, 1988 (Box 15)
      - MEPO at a Glance, 1987-1988 (Box 15)
      - Striving Towards the Twenty-First Century: Building for Tomorrow, 1987-1989 (Box 15)
      - The Future of Engineering: Mosaic of Multiculturalism, 1989-1991 (Box 15)
      - Strategy 2000 Engineering Diversity for the 21st Century, Four-Year Report, 1992-1995, undated (Box 15)
    - Brochures
      - undated (Box 15)
      - MEPO Facts, 1990-1991 (Box 15)
      - MEPO Fact Sheet, 1992-1995 (Box 15)
    - Newsletters
      - Building for Tomorrow, 1990 (Box 15)
      - MEPO Memo, 1984-1988 (Box 15)
    - Proposals
      - Prospectus to General Motors Corporation Includes Three-Year Report of Minority Engineering Program Office, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Reports
      - Engineering Learning Resource Center Tutoring Report, 1988 (Box 15)
      - Outreach Component, circa 1987 (Box 15)
    - Resource Guide, (includes Short History of the Office) 1984-1985 (Box 15)
    - Specific Programs
      - Detroit Area Pre-College Engineering Program (DAP-CEP)
        - Annual Reports 1985-1986 (Box 15)
        - Brochures undated (Box 15)
        - Newsletters
          - Moving Up, 1986-1992, 2 folders (Box 15)
        - Programs
          - Banquet and Awards Ceremony, 1994 (Box 15)
      - Engineering Industrial Support Program
        - Brochures undated (Box 15)
      - Engineering Learning Resource Center
        - Announcements (e-mail printouts) 1997 (Box 15)
      - Professionals-in-Training Program (PTP)
        - Brochures undated (Box 15)
        - Programs 1987-1989 (Box 15)
        - Reports 1985 (Box 15)
      - Select Student Support Service (4'S)
        - Reports
          - Progress Report, 1988 (Box 15)
          - Final Report, 1988 (Box 15)
          - Appendices, 1989 (Box 15)
          - Final Report, 1989 (Box 15)
          - Progress Report, 1990 (Box 15)
          - Final Report, 1990 (Box 15)
      - Summer Engineering Academy
        - Manuals
          - Student and Parent Handbook, 1991 (Box 15)
        - Overviews 1993 (Box 15)
        - Programs 1990 (Box 15)
      - Summer Enrichment Program
        - Programs 1989 (Box 15)
  - Minority Projects Office
    - Brochures undated (Box 15)
    - Newsletters
      - MPO News, 1972 (Box 15)
      - News From the Minority Projects Office, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Mortimer E. Cooley Foundation
    - Development Campaign 1929-1939, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - National Advisory Committee
    - Agendas 1990-1993 (Box 15)
    - Brochures 1989 (Box 15)
    - Directories
      - Membership Directory, 1990-2002, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Proceedings 1986-1987 (Box 15)
  - National Science Foundations Special Projects Program
    - Reports
      - Computers in Engineering Design Education, vol. 1-6, 1966, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - North Campus Planning Committee
    - Reports
      - Faculty Requirement for Office and Laboratory Building, North Campus, 1959 (Box 16)
      - Space Study and Recommendations, 1959 (Box 16)
      - The Utilization of Space, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Office for the Study of Automotive Transportation
    - Reports